Guide to the Harold Edwards Notebooks MC.373
New York University Archives
Harold Edwards Notebooks
1971-2021
New York University Archives
Edwards, Harold M.
Rollin, Betty
MC.373
2 linear feet in 4 manuscript boxes
Harold Edwards (1936-2020) was a mathematician who focused on number theory, algebra, and the history of mathematics. Alongside Bruce Chandler, Edwards co-founded The Mathematical Intelligencer. Edwards wrote expository books on specific theories and functions; textbooks on linear algebra, calculus, and number theory; and essays on constructive mathematics. He graduated from the University of Wisconsin–Madison in 1956, received an Master of Arts from Columbia University in 1957, and a Ph.D from Harvard University in 1961. He joined the faculty at New York University in 1966, and was an emeritus professor from 2002 until his death. The Harold Edwards Notebooks (dated 1971-2021) consists of spiral-bound notebooks containing the travel and research journals of Harold (Hal) Edwards. While the notebooks primarily document the mathematical problems he was working on, they also contain conversations with collaborators and colleagues, observations from his travels, and notes on his writing process.
Scope and Contents
The Harold Edwards Notebooks (dated 1971-2021) consists of spiral-bound notebooks containing the travel and research journals of Harold (Hal) Edwards. While the notebooks primarily document the mathematical problems he was working on, they also contain conversations with collaborators and colleagues, observations from his travels, and notes on his writing process.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Betty Rollin, widow of Harold Edwards, in December 2022; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.094.
Arrangement
Notebooks are arranged in chronological order.
Biographical Note
Harold Edwards (1936-2020) was a mathematician who focused on number theory, algebra, and the history of mathematics. Alongside Bruce Chandler, Edwards co-founded The Mathematical Intelligencer. Edwards wrote expository books on specific theories and functions; textbooks on linear algebra, calculus, and number theory; and essays on constructive mathematics. He graduated from the University of Wisconsin–Madison in 1956, received an Master of Arts from Columbia University in 1957, and a Ph.D from Harvard University in 1961. He joined the faculty at New York University in 1966, and was an emeritus professor from 2002 until his death.
Mathematicians; Mathematics.; Mathematics |x Study and teaching.; Notebooks; Rollin, Betty; Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences
- Notebook, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Notebook, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Notebook, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Notebook, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Notebook, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notebook, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Notebook, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Notebook, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Notebook, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notebook, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Notebook, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Notebook, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notebook, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Notebook, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Notebook, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Notebook, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Notebook, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notebook, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Notebook, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Notebook, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Notebook, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Notebook, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Notebook, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Notes, 2018-2020 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Articles, 2019 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
- The Mathematical Intelligencer, 2020-2021 (Box 4, Folder 9)